Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and
share this video as much as possible.  Today's question for you before looking at the big news.
What is the largest internal organ of the human body?  Option A Heart,
Option B Lungs, Option C
Liver, Option D Pancreas.  Answer this question by
commenting and tell us which state and
city's news do you want to see more?
Tell us by commenting so that we
can show more news of your state or city.  Let us now
see today's quick big news.
Petrol and diesel may become expensive again in India.
BPCL said if the crisis continues, prices are
sure to increase.  Prices have increased thrice in 9 days.
Rajkumar Dubey, director of oil company Bharat Petroleum, said that if the
global energy crisis continues like this, then
another increase in the prices of petrol and diesel in the country is certain.  Petrol and diesel prices have increased thrice in 9 days in India.  On
May 23, the prices were increased by an average of 90 paise
per litre on May 19 and
before that on May 15, the prices were increased by ₹3.
Crude oil prices remain volatile due to the US-Iran war
and
policymakers are now
left with limited options to deal with it.  According to Dubey, there are
currently three main
options open to the government and oil companies to deal with this crisis.  The first option is to
increase fuel prices at petrol pumps.  The
second option is that the oil companies themselves
bear this loss and let the losses increase.   The
third option is that the government should
provide funds to the oil companies through financing.
Crude oil may become cheaper.  Trump
claims agreement to end Iran war is almost
final.  Talked to leaders of Muslim countries.
US President Donald Trump has
claimed that the agreement to end the Iran war is
almost final.  The two
countries are currently working out the final details
and
the agreement is being finalized after talks with Gulf leaders and the Israeli Prime Minister.  Let us
tell you that
Trump has said that under the agreement, the Strait
of Formosa will be reopened and this is the same
sea route through which
about one-fifth of the world's total oil supply passes
and after this news comes,
crude oil prices may fall on Monday.
Unique homework during summer vacation in Haryana.
Entry of AI for the first time.  Students will
analyze newspapers.  Will open a dhaba
and also go to the police station.  For the
first time, AI will be included in the summer homework of government schools in Haryana.
Primary school
students will calculate their daily tasks
and find out
how much time they took to complete them and will do the same tasks the next day with the
help of AI.  We will
get information about saving electricity and will
also analyse the newspapers of 5 days.  There will be
holidays in all the government schools of the state from May 25 to
June 30 and under the Nipun Bharat Abhiyan, the
Education Department has prepared a workbook.
US Secretary of State disappointed over racist remarks against Indians, says every country has
some stupid people.  He is
not a representative of America.  US
Secretary of State Marco Rubio has expressed disappointment over the issue of
racial remarks and discrimination against Indians in America.
He said such statements do
not represent the entire American society.  At a joint press conference
with External Affairs Minister S A Shankar in New Delhi,
Rubio was
asked about incidents of racism against Indians in the US.  On this
he said that there are some stupid people in every country
who say objectionable things online or in public.
But this does
not determine the true identity of a country.
Iran
refuses to hand over uranium to the US, according to reports.  Said this is
not part of the current deal.  Trump had said he would take it up.
Iran has made it clear that
it will not hand over its highly enriched uranium reserves
to America.  According to Reuters,
a senior Iranian official said the current
preliminary agreements do not include the nuclear issue.
And negotiations on Iran's
nuclear program and uranium reserves will take place
later during the final agreement, according to the source.
At present, no such decision has been taken
that uranium will be sent out of the country.
25 to 60% water wastage in big cities of the country.
Excessive water wasted in Mumbai from Bhopal and Indore.
65% water leakage in Indore.  In almost all the
big cities of the country, 25 to 60% of water is being wasted.
Either there are major leakages in the drinking water lines
or illegal connections have been made to the pipeline.  The
situation is that
Mumbai gets a daily water supply of about 3850 MLD i.e.
million litres
and let us tell you that about 30% of this is
considered to be leakage.  Every day about 1000 MLD water is getting
wasted due to pipeline leakage and other reasons.
This wasted water is
more than the total daily requirement of Indore and Bhopal.
Both these cities need only 900 MLD of water every day.
3246 criminals arrested in Tamil Nadu in 3 days.
Anti-Drug Task Force
seized marijuana and drugs from 419 drug smugglers.
Its price is Rs 1 crore 43 lakh.  Tamil Nadu
Police has detained 3246 miscreants
and arrested 419 drug peddlers.
This action has been taken during a special campaign conducted in the last three days.
During the drive, police have
examined 15349 persons and these included 12650
history-sheeters and 2699 non-history-sheeters
and 844 persons were sent
to judicial custody under various legal sections.
Within 48 hours of taking oath as the Chief Minister of Tamil Nadu, Vijay had
taken four major decisions and these included the decision to form
around 65 Anti Drug Task Forces (ANTF) in every district of Tamil Nadu, the
effect of which is now visible.   The
doors of Hemkund Sahib opened after 225 days, the
shrine was decorated with 5 quintals of flowers, 6605
devotees visited, till now
more than 67000 registrations have been done.  The
doors of Shri Hemkund Sahib, the holy shrine of Sikhs located in Chamoli, were opened for the devotees on Saturday morning at 11:30 am
with full rituals and prayers.
More than 3000 devotees from India and abroad were present at the Dham to witness the historic moment of opening of the doors after about 225 days.
Under the leadership of five beloveds, the
first batch of devotees completed the difficult climb from Ghagharia and
reached the shrine situated at an altitude of about 1500 feet and as soon as the doors opened, the entire
Lokpal valley echoed with the chants of Bole Sonihal Sat Sri Akal.  The
Gurudwara was
decorated with about 5 quintals of flowers.
Actress Tisha's funeral took place 12 days after her death.  The
brother performed the last rites in Bhopal.   The
Delhi AIIMS team conducted the post-mortem again.
Actress Tisha was cremated on Sunday, 12 days after her death.
Brother Major Harshit gave Twisha her last rites at Bhadbhada crematorium in Bhopal.
During this, Twisha
's mother and family became emotional and started crying and
before this, on Sunday itself, the Delhi AIIMS
team conducted a second post-mortem of Twisha's dead body.
After the process which lasted for about 3 hours at Bhopal AIIMS, the team left Bhopal.  The
samples and Virya related to the post-mortem were kept safe in Bhopal AIIMS itself.  The
team submitted its report in a sealed envelope.
Cockroach Janata Party founder said that he has got
back the control of his Instagram account.
Sharing the data of followers, he asked why 94% of them are Indians and Riju is
calling them Pakistanis?
Cockroach Janata Party founder Abhijeet
Dipke claimed that he has
regained control of his Instagram account.
He posted a video on Instagram and
wrote, we are back.  You had forgotten.
What can we do to survive?
He also shared an image of a cockroach with the post
and earlier on Saturday
he had claimed that his party and
personal accounts had been hacked.  Meanwhile,
Deepak shared follower data on Instagram on Sunday and
said that more than 94% of his
followers are from India.  He
questioned Union Minister Kiran Reju as to
why Indian youth are being called Pakistanis
?
BJP won for the first time in Falta, Bengal.
Defeated CPI(M) candidate by 109000 votes.  TMC's Jahangir, who withdrew from the election,
got 7783 votes.  BJP has won the election results of Falta seat in West Bengal.
BJP candidate Divyanshu has
won by a margin of more than 1 lakh votes.
He secured over 14,900 votes
and CPI(M) candidate Shambhunath
Kurmi came second with 4,000 votes.
TMC's Jahangir, who retreated in the elections,
remained at fourth place.
BJP has won for the first time in the 74-year history of Falta.  From
1952 to 2006, it
was a stronghold of Congress and CPI(M) and since 2011,
TMC candidates had won here three times in a row.
BJP said that Rahul's plan to topple the Modi government is like
dreaming.  Everyone knows the nature of the toolkit gang.
Rahul had said that Modi
's departure is certain in one year.  BJP has hit back at Rahul Gandhi for predicting the fall of the Central Government.
Maharashtra CM
Devendra Fadnavis said that Rahul Gandhi's
statement is like daydreaming.  Meanwhile,
Union Minister Piyush Goyal said that
Rahul Gandhi's statement points towards a big conspiracy in
which Congress, other
opposition parties and the toolkit gang were involved and these
people together are dreaming of destabilizing India.
Temperature reaches 48 degrees Celsius in six cities of UP.  Temperature crosses 47°C in 12 states including Rajasthan and MP,
97 out of 100 hottest cities in the world are in India.  India featured among the 100
hottest cities in the world on Sunday, with 97 of them being from India.
And
according to private agency eqi.in, six cities of Uttar Pradesh are among the top 10 hottest cities.
Where the
temperature was recorded at 48° Celsius at 2:00 pm and
Prayagraj topped the list.  Temperatures above 47 degrees Celsius were recorded in 37 cities of Uttar Pradesh, Madhya
Pradesh, Rajasthan, Punjab, Bihar, Chhattisgarh,
Andhra Pradesh, Odisha, Telangana,
Uttarakhand, Haryana and
Maharashtra.  The
Meteorological
Department has warned that the
temperature may increase further on 26th and 27th.  Earlier,
Brahmapuri in Maharashtra
remained the hottest city in the country for the second consecutive day with a temperature of 47.1 degrees Celsius.  16 people have died
due to heat stroke in seven districts of Telangana this
summer season.
According to the Meteorological Department, a heat wave alert has been issued till May 26 in
Hyderabad, Reddy, Karim Nagar, Khammam,
Nalgonda, Suryapet, Malugur and Mahbubnagar of Telangana.
People have been advised
not to go out of their homes from 11:00 am to 4:00 pm.
Yogi spoke strictly on the power crisis and said that if there is negligence,
action will be taken.  Energy Minister
entered the field.  Be it village or city, electricity supply should not
stop.  Let us inform that on the power crisis in UP,
CM Yogi Adityanath said that
negligence in power supply will not be tolerated.  If there is
any mistake at any level,
action is certain.  He has asked the Energy Minister and the
Minister of State to go to the field and
inspect the control room.  The CM has
clearly said that uninterrupted power supply should be ensured from villages to cities.
CM Yogi told the officers that if the
power supply is disrupted,
timely and correct information should be given to the general public.  Just
filing a complaint is not enough.
Consumers should also be informed about the
time taken to resolve the problem and this will increase people's confidence.  It
is very important to give timely and correct bills to consumers.  The billing and recovery
system should be further improved.
BJP MLA will ban cockroach party in UP.
Akhilesh's support to CJP.
Rajbhar said that Samajwadi Party has accepted defeat.
Red and black are becoming a hit trend.
Hit Janata Party HJP has made its entry against Cockroach Janata Party CJP.  Due to the
conflict on social media, the youth seem to be divided into two camps.  The
impact of this digital campaign is visible in UP also.  On May 22,
a young man in Mathura reached the Municipal Corporation office wearing a cockroach costume
and
danced to the music.  When asked, he said that he was
angry with the dirty water drains falling into the Yamuna.
This video was shared by Samajwadi Party chief
Akhilesh Yadav.  He extended
his support to this digital campaign on Instagram.
Wrote that now BJP and CJP are
face to face.  At the same time, Cabinet Minister in UP government
Anil Rajbhar called Cockroach Janata
Party just a drama.  In a TV
interview, he said that there is
no threat to BJP from the cockroach Janata Party.   The
opposition has no issues.  That is why he is doing
politics with the help of such trends.
Panchayat elections will be held in UP only after the assembly elections.
Sent the proposal to Yogi.
Administrators will be appointed in Gram Panchayats before May 26.   The
speculations regarding Panchayat elections in UP have ended.  Now the Panchayat elections will be held
only after the 2027 Assembly elections.   The
tenure of the heads of 57695 gram panchayats of the state is
ending after two days on 26th May.
Due to this, the Panchayati Raj Department has sent a proposal to the Chief Minister to appoint an administrator
in the village after the tenure of the Pradhans ends.
Meanwhile, Panchayati Raj
Minister Om Prakash Rajbhar says that the
order has not been issued yet.  The
proposal has been sent to the Chief Minister.  Just a few days
ago, the Panchayati Raj Department had sent a proposal to the Cabinet to
appoint an administrator or form an administrative committee to handle the work after the tenure of the village heads ends.
Department
Director Amit Singh had said that there is no provision for
extending the tenure of village heads
and the administrator will be
appointed at the government level.  There is a provision to
appoint the Gram Panchayat Assistant of the Panchayats as the administrator
and until the elections are held, the
administrator handles the work of the Gram Panchayat.
Today's good thought: A
wise man remains silent because of his wisdom
and a fool thinks that he is
silent because of his fear.  Do let us know how you liked this
video in the comment section.   If you
liked the video then please like and
share the video and to
watch such interesting videos subscribe to our channel Jio News
and press the bell icon and do
check our playlist and community tab to watch our old and latest videos.  So see you in the next video.
Thank you for now.